Ibtasam Ashraf

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

A software professional who is highly knowledgeable in Quality Assurance methodologies and able to perform in a fast-paced agile environment. Experienced in all test activities including planning, test execution, and reporting test results to multiple teams across the organization. Highly organized individual with the ability to troubleshoot complex problems.

ibtasamashraf26@gmail.com



+92 337 7577 368



in linkedin.com/in/ibtasam-ashraf

WORK EXPERIENCE

SQA Engineer Nextbridge

10/2021 - Present

Lahore

Roles & Responsibilities

- Interacted with Business Analysts and Developers in requirements analysis, testing, and documentation of the application.
- Participated in Scrum meetings, reviews, and developed test scenarios.
- Created and executed manual test cases for web applications and mobile applications.
- Logged defects and tracked them using JIRA, Trello & Taiga and coordinated with the development and business teams to resolve the issues/defects.
- Completed training of automation using framework called Cypress.

SQA Trainee

Programmers Force

08/2021 - 10/2021

Lahore

Roles & Responsibilites

- Learned about basics of QA.
- Learned about manual & automation testing.
- Wrote Test Cases & Test Scenarios of company's products.
- Performed basic level of testing on different sample sites.

Customer Support Representative Mindbridge

09/2020 - 07/2021

Lahore

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked as CSR in Uber's support of SSA region.
- Worked as Team Coordinator in the Marketplace Project.
- Worked as Team Coordinator in Sanction Screening Project.

EDUCATION

BS (Hons) - Computer Science University of Eigineering & Technology, Lahore

09/2015 - 06/2020

SKILLS

Manual Testing Test Cases Test Scenarios & Plans UI & Responsive Testing Funtional Testing Postman Cypress

PROJECTS

Regiekr8 - Schoolbee

- A school management system for Dutch clients that will enable users to manage multiple schools, teachers, and students.
- Performed UI & functional testing on various user roles and modules.
- Actively communicated with client and BA regarding requirement gathering and analysis.
- Reported a lot of bugs on JIRA and keep track of them.
- Verified client's feedback and communicated that feedback to the team.

Managed Performance Partners

- US-based electricity-related project where the user is using an iOS application and performs a survey of all electric appliances installed
- The app has to give some recommendations so that the user will save an appropriate amount on a monthly basis while paying his electric
- Performed UI & functional testing on Android and iOS apps.
- Actively communicated with client and team regarding requirement gathering and analysis.
- Reported a lot of bugs on JIRA and keep track of them.

PhonePay

- An iOS and Android app for invoice generation and payment was developed for B2B and B2C purposes.
- Users can generate an invoice for a particular client and send it to the client via email or SMS and the client is able to verify the invoice.
- Performed UI & functional testing on various user roles and modules.
- Actively communicated with client and team regarding requirements
- Reported a lot of bugs on JIRA and keep track of them.

INTERESTS

Football Reading Snooker Cricket